CHRISTOPHER J. BURESCH

OBJECTIVE

Experienced software engineer with a focus on storage and distributed systems. Expert in designing and implementing scalable solutions for handling large amounts of data. Committed to delivering high-performing and reliable systems, utilizing a strong understanding of storage architectures and distributed computing concepts.

SKILLS

Proficient Languages: Scala, Java, Python, C#

Relevant Experience: Scalding / Hadoop MapReduce, HDFS, Airflow, Docker, K8s, Azure/GCP/AWS,

gRPC/thrift/protobuf, Bazel, Puppet, Terraform

Learning Languages: Rust, Go

EXPERIENCE

Twitter, Inc. - Senior Software Engineer

Blobstore (Distributed Object Storage),

Dec 2018 - Nov 2022 Seattle, WA

As a team of 8 we stored 70PB of Twitter's public and private data in an on-prem multi-datacenter distributed key-value system. During my time on the team I owned the hardware health, all service automation, monitoring, tooling and deployments as well as custodial services and processes as well as producing feature work.

Selected Accomplishments

- Designed and implemented chargeback automation to give customers far more granular resource cost across storage class, data locality and replication factor.
- Developed anti-entropy services and tooling to process large metadata dumps to multi-step
- Developed a topology-aware locking service to ensure operation actors could operate independently without affecting service health. This presented other opportunities we were able to exploit like no-touch automated deployments and hardware lifecycle automation.
- Wrote compliance automation for kernel and firmware updates using Airflow as an orchestration engine. Rolls 8k machines across multiple datacenters in less than 30 days with no manual intervention and negligible service interruption.
- Migrated multiple services from baremetal to Aurora Mesos compute clusters to ease operational burden and to improve developer velocity.
- Handled service monitoring and tooling, system health, system config, loadtesting, capacity planning and oncall.

Microsoft Corporation - Software Engineer

Aug 2015 - Nov 2018 Seattle, WA

Dynamics

Worked remote to a small Switzerland-based follow-the-sun cloud infrastructure team tasked with managing the operational health of a Microsoft Social Engagement product's backend. Later switched to a backend product team developing an account management api for Dynamics CRM.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Gonzaga University

2011 - 2015 Spokane, WA

Clubs and Activities

Men's Rowing, Div. 1 2011-12 Computer Science Club 2012-15 Cycling Club 2013-15 ACM ICPC, PNW 2012, '13, '14 Math Club 2013-15 WSU Hackathon 2015

Achievements

3rd On-Site, ACM ICPC (PNW) 2013, 2014

LEADERSHIP

- Mentored new grads and interns with weekly 1:1's and adhoc sessions to help them ramp up into Twitter Engineering!
- Ambassador for Twitter Seattle 2021-2022. Responsible for planning events, creating opportunities for colleagues to socialize, assisting onsite operations management.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Avid Mountain Climber! Summitted Mt. Baker, Mt. Shuksan, and Mt. Hood.
- 3d Printing enthusiast! I solve my everyday problems with plastic.
- I play tabletop, RPG and video games!